<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trevor Piltch</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Trevor Piltch</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PomoBit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/pomo_bit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/pomo_bit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;pomobit&#34;&gt;PomoBit&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trevorpiltch/Pomo-Bit&#34;&gt;Repo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the world of digital distractions, sometimes the best solution is a physical one. This project transforms a &lt;a href=&#34;https://microbit.org/&#34;&gt;Micro:Bit v2&lt;/a&gt; into a dedicated Pomodoro timer, bringing the power of focused work sessions right to your desk.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hardware:&lt;/strong&gt; Utilizes the Micro:Bit v2 platform&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software:&lt;/strong&gt; Written in C using open source HAL libraries&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Functionality:&lt;/strong&gt; Alternates between 25-minute work sessions and 5-minute breaks&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;personal-impact&#34;&gt;Personal Impact&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since implementing this timer, I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that I&amp;rsquo;m more deliberate with my breaks. Before, I used a phone or mac app to track my breaks and ended up wasting my time on email or social media. This provides a visual and tactile separation between work time and break time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OmniSync</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/omnisync/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/omnisync/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;omnisync&#34;&gt;OmniSync&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trevorpiltch/omnifocus-sync&#34;&gt;Repo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;This is a Go-based CLI utility that seamlessly integrates OmniFocus with enterprise platforms (e.g.&#xA;GitHub, Shortcut), featuring comprehensive error handling and close to 90% test coverage&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software:&lt;/strong&gt; Written in Go, utilizing existing open source code&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Features:&lt;/strong&gt; Import issues from any source to a specific OmniFocus project&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical:&lt;/strong&gt; Includes JSON parsing, unit testing, and api handling&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;personal-impact&#34;&gt;Personal Impact&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I use a piece of software more than I use &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.omnigroup.com/omnifocus&#34;&gt;OmniFocus&lt;/a&gt;. Since 2019, I&amp;rsquo;ve kept every actionable item in my life organized in this app. As I got more into software, I realized there wasn&amp;rsquo;t an easy way to sync the various bug tracking tools to OmniFocus. I found a script written &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mikerhodes/github-to-omnifocus&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; (released under the open source ISC license) for syncing GitHub issues to OmniFocus. I loved the tool, although found it restrictive with only importing GitHub issues and only allowing one project at a time. So, I taught myself Go and wrote this project. I now use it everyday (as a toolbar button in OmniFocus) to stay in sync between OmniFocus, GitHub Issues, and Shortcut Stories.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bessel Function of the First Kind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/bessel_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/bessel_function/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-bessel-function-of-the-first-kind&#34;&gt;The Bessel Function of the First Kind&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I took differential equations in the winter of my first year at McGill. I absolutely loved that class and spent a lot of time after class talking to the professor and spending time learning other aspects of this field of math. One day, we learned about the Frobenius method of solving diff-eqs. Curious, I looked up what I could apply the method to, and found the Bessel Function. I tried deriving the function and wrote up my work below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flight Computer Software Lead</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/experience/mrt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/experience/mrt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;flight-computer-software-lead&#34;&gt;Flight Computer Software Lead&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mcgillrocketteam.com/&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The McGill Rocket Team (MRT) is a completely student run design team, focused on designing and launching a hybrid engine rocket. I joined the Flight Computer Software project in my first year at the university, and quickly gained an interest in the work. My first project was fixing a timing issue with an I2C bus. I then worked with another member to implement drivers for new acceleration, temperature, and pressure sensors. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;I was then elected by the team captains to become the new project lead in May 2024. Our planned launch was late August 2024 (at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.launchcanada.org/&#34;&gt;Launch Canada&lt;/a&gt; competition), and I worked throughout the summer to get the system ready for launch. In this time, I re-designed the system to use FreeRTOS and concurrent programming techniques (mutexes, queues, threads, etc.). I also implemented new commands to interface with the propulsion, radio, and payload systems over CAN buses, exhaustively tested a new SD card driver, and implemented a driver for a new video recorder inside the rocket. Although the rocket ultimately didn&amp;rsquo;t fly (due to a faulty fuel valve), the software system worked throughout the testing and various launch attempts. After the competition, I designed the new software system architecture, trained new members, and managed my team of around 8-9 people. I hosted weekly meetings along with work sessions and social events such as hackathons and team wide BBQs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VP Finance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/experience/miae/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/experience/miae/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;vp-finance&#34;&gt;VP Finance&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://studentpresidentmi.wixsite.com/website&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The McGill Institute for Aerospace Engineering is a collection of McGill professors, students, and Montreal professionals, looking to advance research and knowledge in aerospace engineering. As VP finance for the student executive committee, I manage a budget exceeding $3,000. I ensure the strategic allocation of resources for impactful student events and educational workshops. By carefully balancing financial constraints with programming goals, I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully facilitated numerous guest speaker events, providing valuable networking and learning opportunities for our members.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Meditation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/meditation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;o1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O(1)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01010100 01101000 01101001 01101110 01101011 00100000 01000100 01101001&#xA;01100110 01100110 01100101 01110010 01100101 01101110 01110100 00101110&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;00000001&#34;&gt;00000001&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To start, you sit down with a mug full of Red Bull because you&amp;rsquo;re scared&#xA;that you&amp;rsquo;ll fall asleep. You flip open your Mac and hear the iconic&#xA;chime. The machine whirs to life, opens its eyes and greets you with the&#xA;familiar, &lt;em&gt;please enter your password&lt;/em&gt;. With the Mac fully awake, you&#xA;can begin your process. Most importantly, is the music, so you open the&#xA;music app and put on some AC/DC. You know you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t listen to music&#xA;this loud at 11 p.m., but you also should be asleep, so you don&amp;rsquo;t really&#xA;care.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grover&#39;s Algorithm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/grovers_algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/grovers_algorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;grovers-algorithm&#34;&gt;Grovers Algorithm&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trevorpiltch/Grovers-Algorithm&#34;&gt;Repo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;For my final project in CS590 (Computer Architecture) at Phillips Exeter Academy, I delved into the cutting-edge world of quantum computing by implementing &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grover%27s_algorithm&#34;&gt;Grover&amp;rsquo;s search algorithm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;highlights&#34;&gt;Highlights&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Algorithm:&lt;/strong&gt; Grover&amp;rsquo;s algorithm, a quantum method for unstructured search&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Performance:&lt;/strong&gt; Achieves \(O(\sqrt({N}))\), showcasing quantum speedup&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Framework:&lt;/strong&gt; Implemented using IBM&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ibm.com/quantum/qiskit&#34;&gt;Qiskit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;learning-outcomes&#34;&gt;Learning Outcomes&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This project provided hands-on experience with:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Quantum gates and their implementations&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Practical application of quantum computing concepts&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Advanced mathematical principles in computing&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;While the underlying mathematics and physics proved challenging, this project significantly enhanced my understanding of quantum computing principles and their potential impact on future computer architectures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blood Cobalt; How International Institutions Failed the Democratic Republic of Congo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/his_577/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/his_577/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;blood-cobalt-how-the-international-institutions-failed-the-democratic-republic-of-congo&#34;&gt;Blood Cobalt How the International Institutions Failed the Democratic Republic of Congo&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The glamorous shop displays and marketing of state-of-the-art technologies are a stark contrast to the children carrying bags of rocks, and miners in narrow manmade tunnels risking permanent lung damage.&#xA;— Mark Dummett, Researcher at Amnesty International&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite being the largest country in sub-Saharan Africa, the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC) is one of the poorest nations in the world. According to the World Bank, 64% of its 97 million citizens live on less than \$2.15 a day. The Congolese economy relies heavily on mining, especially of Cobalt. The mineral is essential in lithium-ion batteries, which power everything from phones to electric cars, and 74% of the world&amp;rsquo;s supply comes from the Congo. Cobalt dust is also toxic to breathe and touch, but “artisanal miners” axe away at the mineral all day with nothing but their hands and pickaxes. However, this Cobalt economy is not an accident because the DRC has been purposefully underdeveloped throughout its history. After the Congo’s independence in 1960, the World Bank and IMF shaped the new economy to become heavily reliant on mining while underfunding public infrastructure. This gave western companies the power to exploit resources with very little oversight and high margins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead Developer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/experience/wheels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/experience/wheels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;wheels&#34;&gt;Wheels&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/wheels-skateboarding-buddy/id1667530731?itsct=apps_box_badge&amp;amp;itscg=30200&#34;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I got interested in skateboarding over the COVID-19 pandemic, and bought a 7.5&amp;quot; Alienware board to learn. I rode the board almost everyday through my neighborhood, and I wanted to know how fast and far I was going. Since I had just learned Swift a year before, I figured that this was a good opportunity to build a mobile app. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;The app was released to the public in early 2023 and has reached over 500 downloads on every continent. The pace of growth has increased as well, with almost 200 new users joining in the last two months alone. The app has also had a favorable rating on the app store, consitently with 5.0/5.0 stars.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Labs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/project/labs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/project/labs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;labs&#34;&gt;Labs&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trevorpiltch/Labs&#34;&gt;Repo&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br&gt;&#xA;Have you ever found yourself stuck in a cycle of passive learning, endlessly consuming books and videos without making tangible progress? I&amp;rsquo;ve been there too. This project is my answer to that common pitfall.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This repository serves as my personal &amp;ldquo;lab&amp;rdquo; for learning. It&amp;rsquo;s a curated collection of:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Projects:&lt;/strong&gt; applications built from tutorials&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scripts:&lt;/strong&gt; small, focused code snippets to test ideas&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-repo&#34;&gt;Current Repo&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Currently, the repository contains the following repos: &lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/trevorpiltch/Depot-Tutorial/tree/76b1f65ce90b76eb41eec5750ddd0138b58d8f59&#34;&gt;Depo Tutorial:&lt;/a&gt; the demo application &lt;a href=&#34;https://pragprog.com/titles/rails6/agile-web-development-with-rails-6/#resource&#34;&gt;Agile Web Development with Rails 6&lt;/a&gt; which I used to teach myself Ruby and Ruby on Rails.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lead Mobile Developer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/experience/aa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/experience/aa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;lead-mobile-developer&#34;&gt;Lead Mobile Developer&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.alwaysart.com/&#34;&gt;Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;about&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;AlwaysArt is a startup based in California looking to connect artists, galleries, and collectors. I built their internal app in Swift and SwiftUI, interfacing with the live production backend (running on Ruby on Rails). The app helped increase inventory management from around 200 items to over 20000 utilizing QR code scanning and a responsive UI. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;When the company wanted to release their mobile application, the CEO hired me to build it for them. I expanded the iOS application to include a consumer facing side, that includes an artwork photo gallery, artwork lookup, and full account management. I also added system integration through widgets and spotlight to enhance the user experience. &lt;br&gt;&#xA;I then taught myself JetPack compose and Kotlin to implement the app for android devices. This was a fun challenge, as I had never done android development before. The android app has feature parity with the iOS app, and includes the same system integrations, providing a consistent look and feature set.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
