<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Trevor Piltch</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Trevor Piltch</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On the Launch of Robot Forest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/19_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/19_01/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;release-early-and-often&#34;&gt;Release Early and Often.&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Welcome to 2025! I&amp;rsquo;m a couple weeks late, but one of my resolutions was to start writing more and this represents my first step in that journey.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a busy start to 2025 and I just recently launched my new developer studio &lt;a href=&#34;https://robotforest.dev&#34;&gt;Robot Forest&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to launch this thing for years, and finally got the confidence to do so over the holidays. I also finally submitted version 3.0 of my app, &lt;a href=&#34;https://wheels.trevorpiltch.com&#34;&gt;Wheels&lt;/a&gt;, to the app store. This has been one of those projects that I&amp;rsquo;ve been consistently tweaking for almost two years. Every time I thought I&amp;rsquo;d release it, I&amp;rsquo;d come up with another feature to add, implement it, and then repeat the process. With something like this, I think I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that the most important thing is to follow the old software mantra, release early and often. For the longest time, I was the only one with eyes on this version and was overly critical of every detail. By releasing it to the public, I&amp;rsquo;ve already gotten new feedback and praise about the new features. While not the biggest achievement so far, I&amp;rsquo;m definitely proud of this one and excited to break the cycle of feature bloating.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bessel Function of the First Kind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/bessel_function/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/bessel_function/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-bessel-function-of-the-first-kind&#34;&gt;The Bessel Function of the First Kind&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I took differential equations in the winter of my first year at McGill. I absolutely loved that class and spent a lot of time after class talking to the professor and spending time learning other aspects of this field of math. One day, we learned about the Frobenius method of solving diff-eqs. Curious, I looked up what I could apply the method to, and found the Bessel Function. I tried deriving the function and wrote up my work below.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Meditation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/meditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/meditation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;o1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;O(1)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;01010100 01101000 01101001 01101110 01101011 00100000 01000100 01101001&#xA;01100110 01100110 01100101 01110010 01100101 01101110 01110100 00101110&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;00000001&#34;&gt;00000001&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To start, you sit down with a mug full of Red Bull because you&amp;rsquo;re scared&#xA;that you&amp;rsquo;ll fall asleep. You flip open your Mac and hear the iconic&#xA;chime. The machine whirs to life, opens its eyes and greets you with the&#xA;familiar, &lt;em&gt;please enter your password&lt;/em&gt;. With the Mac fully awake, you&#xA;can begin your process. Most importantly, is the music, so you open the&#xA;music app and put on some AC/DC. You know you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t listen to music&#xA;this loud at 11 p.m., but you also should be asleep, so you don&amp;rsquo;t really&#xA;care.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blood Cobalt; How International Institutions Failed the Democratic Republic of Congo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/his_577/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/his_577/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;blood-cobalt-how-the-international-institutions-failed-the-democratic-republic-of-congo&#34;&gt;Blood Cobalt How the International Institutions Failed the Democratic Republic of Congo&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The glamorous shop displays and marketing of state-of-the-art technologies are a stark contrast to the children carrying bags of rocks, and miners in narrow manmade tunnels risking permanent lung damage.&#xA;— Mark Dummett, Researcher at Amnesty International&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Despite being the largest country in sub-Saharan Africa, the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC) is one of the poorest nations in the world. According to the World Bank, 64% of its 97 million citizens live on less than \$2.15 a day. The Congolese economy relies heavily on mining, especially of Cobalt. The mineral is essential in lithium-ion batteries, which power everything from phones to electric cars, and 74% of the world&amp;rsquo;s supply comes from the Congo. Cobalt dust is also toxic to breathe and touch, but “artisanal miners” axe away at the mineral all day with nothing but their hands and pickaxes. However, this Cobalt economy is not an accident because the DRC has been purposefully underdeveloped throughout its history. After the Congo’s independence in 1960, the World Bank and IMF shaped the new economy to become heavily reliant on mining while underfunding public infrastructure. This gave western companies the power to exploit resources with very little oversight and high margins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
